<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../js.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>JavaScript Line Plot</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    A line plot using a JavaScript based charting library.
	</shortDescription>
		
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
    	    <p>A line plot using a JavaScript based charting library. The view can be accessed either via
            the <i>Interactive View</i> action on the executed node or in the KNIME Web Portal. 
	       	</p>
            <p>The configuration of the node lets you choose the size of a sample to display and to enable certain 
            controls, which are then available in the view. This includes the ability to choose different columns
            for x and y or the possibility to set a title. Enabling or disabling these controls via the configuration
            dialog might not seem useful at first glance but has benefits when used in a web portal/wizard execution 
            where the end user has no access to the workflow itself.
            </p>
            <p>The second input port provides the possibility to specify colors for the different lines/columns in the plot. Therefore append a Extract Column Header and Transpose node to the data table which should be plotted in this node. Afterwards use the Color Manager to append the colors based on the individual column names. The node automatically selects the column from the Color Manager and assigns the color values to the plotted columns.</p>
            <p>Additionally a static SVG image can be rendered, which is then made available at the first output port.</p>
            <p>Note, this node is currently under development. Future versions of the node might have more or changed functionality.</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Scatter Plot Options">
            <option name="Hide in wizard">If the view should be hidden in the wizard execution.</option>
            <option name="Create image at outport">If an image is supposed to be rendered during execute for the upper outport. Disable this option if image is not needed or creation is too time consuming.</option>
            <option name="Maximum number of rows">Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for this visualization.</option>
            <option name="Selection column name">Name of the appended column containing boolean values to indicate, whether a point was selected in the view or not.</option>
            <option name="Choose column for x-axis">Defines the column that contains the values for X coordinates.</option>
            <option name="Choose columns for y-axis">Defines the columns that contains the values for Y coordinates. Every included column is represented by one line in the view.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Axis Configuration">
            <option name="Label for x-axis" optional="true">The label for the x-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
            <option name="Label for y-axis" optional="true">The label for the y-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
            <option name="Date format">A format string, required when displaying dates and times on an axis.</option>
            <option name="Show color legend">Switches the legend on/off. The legend shows the mapping between colors used in the view and the respective column names.</option>
            <option name="Auto range axes">Select if axes ranges are supposed to be automatically calculated. This also applies if the columns are changed in the view.</option>
            <option name="Use domain information">Using this option, the axis ranges are determined by bounds from the domain on initial layout.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="General Plot Options">
            <option name="Chart title" optional="true">The title of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no title will be shown.</option>
            <option name="Chart subtitle" optional="true">The subtitle of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no subtitle will be shown.</option>
            <option name="Width of image (in px)">The width of the generated SVG image.</option>
            <option name="Height of image (in px)">The height of the generated SVG image.</option>
            <option name="Resize view to fill window">Setting this option resizes the view to the available area of the window. If disabled the view size is static according to the set width and height.</option>
            <option name="Background color">The color of the background of the image.</option>
            <option name="Data area color">The background color of the data area, within the axes.</option>
            <option name="Show grid">If an additional grid is being rendered at the axes tick positions.</option>
            <option name="Grid color">The color of the grid.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="View Controls">
            <option name="Enable view edit controls">If checked all edit controls selected below will be rendered in the view. Unchecking this option disables all edit controls.</option>
            <option name="Enable title edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart title in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable subtitle edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart subtitle in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable column chooser for x-axis">Renders a selection box to change column used for X coordinates in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable column chooser for y-axis">Renders a selection box to change column used for X coordinates in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable label edit for x-axis">Renders a text box to change x-axis label in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable label edit for y-axis">Renders a text box to change y-axis label in the view.</option>
            <option name="Enable mouse crosshair">Enables the display of additional crosshairs with labels of the current mouse position.</option>
            <option name="Snap to data points">If enabled the crosshairs will snap to the closest data point according to mouse position.</option>
            <option name="Enable selection">Enables or disables the selection feature. When enabled data points can be selected in the scatter plot and the selection is propagated in an appended column of the data table.</option>
            <option name="Enable rectangular selection">Enables a selection mode where a rectangle can be drawn to select points. To start drawing a selection rectangle hold down the Alt-Key and drag the mouse.</option>
            <option name="Enable lasso selection">Enables a selection mode where a freeform shape can be drawn to select points. To start drawing a selection lasso hold down the Ctrl and Alt-Key and drag the mouse.</option>
            <option name="Enable panning">Enable panning on the plot. To start panning click and drag the mouse. Note if panning and drag zooming is enabled, 
                panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.</option>
            <option name="Enable mouse wheel zooming">Enable zooming on the plot using the mouse wheel.</option>
            <option name="Enable drag zooming">Enable zooming on the plot by dragging the mouse and drawing a zoom rectangle. Dragging from the top-left down 
                will create a zoom rectangle, dragging from the bottom right up will reset the zoom to fit the extends of the plot. Note if panning and 
                drag zooming is enabled, panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.
            </option>
            <option name="Show zoom reset button">Renders a button to resize the plot to it's extends.</option>
        </tab>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<interactiveView name="Line Plot">
		Displays a line plot visualization of the input data.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Display data">Data table with data to display.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Line color data" optional="true">Data table containing one column with the column names of table which has in addition a color assigned.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Image">SVG image rendered by the JavaScript implementation of the line plot.</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Input data and view selection">Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that represents the selection made in the line plot view.</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>