<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../js.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>JavaScript Scatter Plot</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	    A scatter plot using a JavaScript based charting library.
	</shortDescription>
		
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>		
    	    <p>A scatter plot using a JavaScript based charting library. The view can be accessed either via
            the "interactive view" action on the executed node or in KNIME Server web portal page. 
	       	</p>
            <p>The configuration of the node lets you choose the size of a sample to display and to enable certain 
            controls, which are then available in the view. This includes the ability to choose different columns
            for x and y or the possibility to set a title. Enabling or disabling these controls via the configuration
            dialog might not seem useful at first glance but has benefits when used in a web portal/wizard execution 
            where the end user has no access to the workflow itself.
            </p>
            <p>Note, this node is currently under development. Future versions of the node will have more functionality,
            including the ability to generate a static view/image output.</p> 
		</intro>
		<option name="Maximum number of rows">Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for this visualization.</option>
		<option name="Enable view edit controls">If checked all edit controls selected below will be rendered in the view. Unchecking this option disables all edit controls.</option>
		<option name="Chart Title" optional="true">The title of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no title will be shown.</option>
		<option name="Chart Subtitle" optional="true">The subtitle of the graph shown above the generated image. If left blank, no subtitle will be shown.</option>
		<option name="Enable title edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart title in the view.</option>
		<option name="Enable subtitle edit controls">Renders a text box to change the chart subtitle in the view.</option>
		<option name="Choose column for x-axis">Defines the column that contains the values for X coordinates.</option>
		<option name="Choose column for y-axis">Defines the column that contains the values for Y coordinates.</option>
		<option name="Enable column chooser for x-axis">Renders a selection box to change column used for X coordinates in the view.</option>
		<option name="Enable column chooser for y-axis">Renders a selection box to change column used for X coordinates in the view.</option>
		<option name="Label for x-axis" optional="true">The label for the x-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
		<option name="Label for y-axis" optional="true">The label for the y-axis. If left blank, the selected column name is displayed.</option>
		<option name="Enable label edit for x-axis">Renders a text box to change x-axis label in the view.</option>
		<option name="Enable label edit for y-axis">Renders a text box to change y-axis label in the view.</option>
		<option name="Enable panning">Enable panning on the plot. To start panning click and drag the mouse. Note if panning and drag zooming is enabled, 
		    panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.</option>
		<option name="Enable mouse wheel zooming">Enable zooming on the plot using the mouse wheel.</option>
		<option name="Enable drag zooming">Enable zooming on the plot by dragging the mouse and drawing a zoom rectangle. Dragging from the top-left down 
		    will create a zoom rectangle, dragging from the bottom right up will reset the zoom to fit the extends of the plot. Note if panning and 
		    drag zooming is enabled, panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.
		</option>
		<option name="Show zoom reset button">Renders a button to resize the plot to it's extends.</option>
	</fullDescription>
	
	<interactiveView name="Scatter Plot">
		Displays a scatter plot visualization of the input data.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Display data">Data table with data to display.</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Image">SVG image rendered by the JavaScript implementation of the scatter plot.</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Input data and view selection">Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that represents the selection made in the scatter plot view.</outPort>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>